{
  "translations": {
    "en": {
      "q3": {
        "type":"select",
        "description":"<b>Lemma</b>: If<br/>&nbsp; &nbsp; $(q_1, w_1\\underline{a_1}u_1) \\vdash_M^* (q_2, w_2\\underline{a_2}u_2)$ for string $w$ and <br/>&nbsp; &nbsp; $(q_2, w_2\\underline{a_2}u_2) \\vdash^*_M (q_3, w_3\\underline{a_3}u_3)$ then <br/> &nbsp; &nbsp; $(q_1, w_1\\underline{a_1}u_1) \\vdash^*_M (q_3, w_3\\underline{a_3}u_3)$.",
        "question":"What does this configuration $(q_1, w_1\\underline{a_1}u_1)$ mean?",
        "answer":["The machine is in state $q_1$", "The read/write head is on the symbol $a_1$"],
        "choices": ["The machine is in state $q_1$", "The read/write head is on the symbol $a_1$"]
      },
      "q4": {
        "type":"select",
        "description":"<b>Lemma</b>: If<br/>&nbsp; &nbsp; $(q_1, w_1\\underline{a_1}u_1) \\vdash_M^* (q_2, w_2\\underline{a_2}u_2)$ for string $w$ and <br/>&nbsp; &nbsp; $(q_2, w_2\\underline{a_2}u_2) \\vdash^*_M (q_3, w_3\\underline{a_3}u_3)$ then <br/> &nbsp; &nbsp; $(q_1, w_1\\underline{a_1}u_1) \\vdash^*_M (q_3, w_3\\underline{a_3}u_3)$.",
        "question":"What do we mean by $\\vdash_M^*$?",
        "answer":"The machine will do zero or more transitions",
        "choices": ["The machine will do zero or more transitions", "The machine will do one transitions"]
      },
      "q5": {
        "type":"select",
        "description":"<b>Lemma</b>: If<br/>&nbsp; &nbsp; $(q_1, w_1\\underline{a_1}u_1) \\vdash_M^* (q_2, w_2\\underline{a_2}u_2)$ for string $w$ and <br/>&nbsp; &nbsp; $(q_2, w_2\\underline{a_2}u_2) \\vdash^*_M (q_3, w_3\\underline{a_3}u_3)$ then <br/> &nbsp; &nbsp; $(q_1, w_1\\underline{a_1}u_1) \\vdash^*_M (q_3, w_3\\underline{a_3}u_3)$.",
        "question":"What do we mean by<br/>$(q_1, w_1\\underline{a_1}u_1) \\vdash_M^* (q_2, w_2\\underline{a_2}u_2)$?",
        "answer":["The machine will change the state from $q_1$ to $q_2$", "The tape content will be modified from $w_1a_1u_1$ to $w_2a_2u_2$", "The head will be on the symbol $a_2$"],
        "choices": ["The machine will change the state from $q_1$ to $q_2$", "The tape content will be modified from $w_1a_1u_1$ to $w_2a_2u_2$", "The head will be on the symbol $a_2$"]
      },
      "q6": {
        "type":"select",
        "description":"<b>Lemma</b>: If<br/>&nbsp; &nbsp; $(q_1, w_1\\underline{a_1}u_1) \\vdash_M^* (q_2, w_2\\underline{a_2}u_2)$ for string $w$ and <br/>&nbsp; &nbsp; $(q_2, w_2\\underline{a_2}u_2) \\vdash^*_M (q_3, w_3\\underline{a_3}u_3)$ then <br/> &nbsp; &nbsp; $(q_1, w_1\\underline{a_1}u_1) \\vdash^*_M (q_3, w_3\\underline{a_3}u_3)$.",
        "question":"In other words, the machine did some processing on the tape content and modified it accordingly.",
        "answer":"True",
        "choices": []
      },
      "q7": {
        "type":"select",
        "description":"<b>Lemma</b>: If<br/>&nbsp; &nbsp; $(q_1, w_1\\underline{a_1}u_1) \\vdash_M^* (q_2, w_2\\underline{a_2}u_2)$ for string $w$ and <br/>&nbsp; &nbsp; $(q_2, w_2\\underline{a_2}u_2) \\vdash^*_M (q_3, w_3\\underline{a_3}u_3)$ then <br/> &nbsp; &nbsp; $(q_1, w_1\\underline{a_1}u_1) \\vdash^*_M (q_3, w_3\\underline{a_3}u_3)$.",
        "question":"What do we mean by<br/>$(q_2, w_2\\underline{a_2}u_2) \\vdash_M^* (q_3, w_3\\underline{a_3}u_3)$?",
        "answer":["The machine will change the state from $q_2$ to $q_3$", "The tape content will be modified from $w_2a_2u_2$ to $w_3a_3u_3$", "The head will be on the symbol $a_3$"],
        "choices": ["The machine will change the state from $q_2$ to $q_3$", "The tape content will be modified from $w_2a_2u_2$ to $w_3a_3u_3$", "The head will be on the symbol $a_3$"]
      },
      "q8": {
        "type":"select",
        "description":"<b>Lemma</b>: If<br/>&nbsp; &nbsp; $(q_1, w_1\\underline{a_1}u_1) \\vdash_M^* (q_2, w_2\\underline{a_2}u_2)$ for string $w$ and <br/>&nbsp; &nbsp; $(q_2, w_2\\underline{a_2}u_2) \\vdash^*_M (q_3, w_3\\underline{a_3}u_3)$ then <br/> &nbsp; &nbsp; $(q_1, w_1\\underline{a_1}u_1) \\vdash^*_M (q_3, w_3\\underline{a_3}u_3)$.",
        "question":"In other words, the machine did <b>more</b> processing on the tape contents and modified it accordingly.",
        "answer":"True",
        "choices": []
      },
      "q9": {
        "type":"select",
        "description":"<b>Lemma</b>: If<br/>&nbsp; &nbsp; $(q_1, w_1\\underline{a_1}u_1) \\vdash_M^* (q_2, w_2\\underline{a_2}u_2)$ for string $w$ and <br/>&nbsp; &nbsp; $(q_2, w_2\\underline{a_2}u_2) \\vdash^*_M (q_3, w_3\\underline{a_3}u_3)$ then <br/> &nbsp; &nbsp; $(q_1, w_1\\underline{a_1}u_1) \\vdash^*_M (q_3, w_3\\underline{a_3}u_3)$.",
        "question":"So, in general we can say that the machine started at $q_1$ with tape content $w_1a_1u_1$, did some processing to it, and ended at $q_3$ with tape content changed to $w_3a_3u_3$.",
        "answer":"True",
        "choices": []
      },
      "q13": {
        "type":"select",
        "description":"Here are some basic machines and notation.<br/>&bull; $|\\Sigma|$ symbol-writing machines (one for each symbol): Any given symbol $\\sigma$ has a symbol-writing machine named $\\sigma$.",
        "question":"If $\\Sigma = \\{a, b\\}$, what does the TM $a$ do?",
        "answer":"write the symbol $a$ to the tape",
        "choices": ["write the symbol $a$ to the tape", "$a$ is just a symbol in the alphabet set $\\Sigma$"]
      },
      "q14": {
        "type":"select",
        "description":"Here are some basic machines and notation.<br/>&bull; Head-moving machines, named $R$, $L$ and $S$, move the head appropriately.",
        "question":"What does the TM $R$ do?",
        "answer":"This TM moves the head to the Right",
        "choices": ["This TM moves the head to the Right", "This TM moves the head to the Left", "This TM makes the head Stay on the current cell"]
      },
      "q15": {
        "type":"select",
        "description":"Here are some basic machines and notation.<br/>&bull; Transitions on anything other than (for example) $\\#$ are labeled $\\overline{\\#}$",
        "question":"What does a tranistion labled with $\\overline{a}$ mean?",
        "answer":"Change the state if the TM machine reads anything except $a$",
        "choices": ["Change the state if the TM machine reads anything except $a$", "Change the state if the TM machine reads $a$"]
      },
      "q16": {
        "type":"select",
        "description":"Here are some basic machines and notation.<br/>&bull; Multiple copies of a machine get a superscript.",
        "question":"$R^3$ means move the read/write head to the right 3 times.",
        "answer":"True",
        "choices": []
      },
      "q18": {
        "type":"select",
        "description":"Let's look at an example.",
        "question":"Which machine will be done first?",
        "answer":"$M_1$",
        "choices": ["$M_1$", "$M_2$", "$M_3$"]
      },
      "q19": {
        "type":"select",
        "description":"Let's look at an example:",
        "question":"Which machine will be done after $M_1$ ends execution when the current tape cell contains $a$?",
        "answer":"$M_2$",
        "choices": ["$M_1$", "$M_2$", "$M_3$"]
      },
      "q20": {
        "type":"select",
        "description":"Let's look at an example:",
        "question":"Which machine will be done after $M_1$ ends execution when the current tape cell contains $b$?",
        "answer":"$M_3$",
        "choices": ["$M_1$", "$M_2$", "$M_3$"]
      },
      "q21": {
        "type":"select",
        "description":"Consider this example:",
        "question":"What does this machine do?",
        "answer":"Move the head right until an empty cell is found",
        "choices": ["Move the head right until an empty cell is found", "Move the head right until a non-empty cell is found"]
      },
      "q22": {
        "type":"select",
        "description":"Consider this example<br/>We will use the notation $R_\\#$ for this process.",
        "question":"What does $R_\\#$ machine do?",
        "answer":"Move the head right until an empty cell is found",
        "choices": ["Move the head right until an empty cell is found", "Move the head right until a non-empty cell is found"]
      },
      "q23": {
        "type":"select",
        "description":"Consider this example:",
        "question":"What does this machine do?",
        "answer":["Move the head left until an empty cell is found", "Once the empty cell is reached, the machine $M$ will run"],
        "choices": ["Move the head left until an empty cell is found", "Once the empty cell is reached, the machine $M$ will run"]
      },
      "q24": {
        "type":"select",
        "description":"Consider this example<br/>We will use the notation $L_\\#$ for the Machine that will go left until it finds an empty cell.",
        "question":"What does the machine to the right of the vertical line do?",
        "answer":["Move the head left until an empty cell is found", "Once the empty cell is reached, the machine $M$ will run"],
        "choices": ["Move the head left until an empty cell is found", "Once the empty cell is reached, the machine $M$ will run"]
      }
    }
  }
}
